Lucas Ferreira de Souza

Ap 2 29 Nelson Street - Phibsborough - Dublin 7 - Ireland | +353 83 827 5937

lukfdg@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucasferreiradesouza/

Personal Profile

Bilingual (Portuguese and English) currently living in Ireland in order to expand my career and improve my IT qualification through study(2nd year Bachelor Science in Computing). Friendly, dynamic, highly motivated, responsible with a great eye for detail. I have around 5 years of experience in E-Commerce managing tool like HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery and Database(MySql).

Objective

Seeking a position in IT area where my education, qualifications and acquired skills will be utilized to their best to improve the company's overall performance and to build on experience gained.

Education and Qualification

2019 – 2021 BSc in Science in Computing and Multimedia – Dorset College Dublin.

Core Modules: Object-Oriented Programming, Front-End Development, Back-End Development, DevOps, Mobile Applications, UX/UI Design & Usability, Mathematics for IT, Operating Systems & Administration, Database Storage & Database Management, Information Systems, Network Routing & Switching, Cyber Security Defense & Operations and Software Engineering.

2006 – 2010 BSc in Business Administration – Sant 'Anna University Centre.

Core Modules: Accounting, Budget and Financial Management, Cost Analysis, Controllership, Logistics and Distribution, Export Management, Foundations of Business Administration and Marketing, Macroeconomics, Computer Applications, Statistics and Mathematics, Marketing Communications, International Business, Enterprise Management.

Relevant Work Experience

Mitie Group PLC, Dublin | July 2017 - Current work.

- Facilities Leader
- Strong relationships with the client and embed a culture of "Service Excellence" solving day to day problems.
- Stock control and management, making weekly orders and budget analysis.
- Interpretation and production of risk assessment health & safety documentation.
- Responsible for staff training and monthly evaluation to ensure the performance of the team.
- Lead and mentor a multi-disciplinary team of personnel.

McDonald's, Dublin | Jun 2018 – Sep 2019

- > Customer Experience Leader
- Responsible for welcome customers into the restaurant and creating "feel-good moments" during their visit.
- Working closely with the management team suggesting improvements to customer service experience.
- Assisting customers on their journey, making their experience easier and enjoyable.
- Speaking knowledgeably about the business, helping customers with any issues or complaints.
- Working with the kitchen staff ensuring high quality in the product delivered.

Leevin Ireland, Dublin | Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

- Social Media Intern
- Monitor and evaluate online social media and advertising content in accordance to policies.
- Visually navigate and review images and text-based content through internally developed applications.
- Partaking in client meetings to communicate findings and research and recommendations.
- Generating excellent quality reports using software systems and applications.
- Campaign review using Adobe Package (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere and After Effects).

Fast Shop S/A (e-Commerce), São Paulo, Brazil | Jan 2016 - Nov 2016

- > E-mail Marketing Specialist
- CRM concepts and database marketing such as: segmentation, marketing 1 to 1, lifecycle and relationship rules.
- E-mail marketing speaker and responsible for training and workflow documentation.
- Process mapping and workflow improvement using tools like Runrun.it and Trello.
- Branding strategy, and analysis of results creating dashboards and excel spreadsheets.
- HTML/CSS code reviewer (Structure, Lines, Links and Tags), uploading and testing campaigns.
- Database management using SQL/jQuery, creating, editing, and integrating lists defining the best strategies.
- Trigger campaigns setup, FTP structure, Multi-Step workflow automations and Spam control.

Máquina de Vendas (e-Commerce), São Paulo, Brazil / Jan 2015 – Dec 2015

- > E-mail Marketing Coordinator
- Management Area, Team development and E-mail Marketing Speaker.
- Monitoring, optimization of indicators (KPIs) relationship actions, email best practices (CRM).
- HTML/CSS code reviewer (Structure, Lines, Links and Tags), uploading and testing campaigns.
- Negotiation with the commercial department, strategy development and market analysis interface.
- Workflow management with the creative team, suppliers and partners (acquisition of new technologies).
- Spam, Phishing and Domain management using Return Path application.

Enext Marketing Services, Sao Paulo, Brazil | May 2012 - Dec 2014

- ➤ E-mail Marketing Coordinator | Jan 2014 Dec 2014
- > E-mail Marketing Analyst | May 2012 Dec 2013
- Operation in Marketing tools (Salesforce Marketing Cloud, Oracle Cloud Responsys, Mailchimp, HubSpot).
- Analysis and reports Google Analytics; Implementation of best practices and Return Path Certification.
- Elaboration of strategies based on segmentation, CRM and behavior.
- Database operation, creating lists, user groups by using jQuery and Trigger campaigns setup.
- HTML/CSS developer (Focused on e-mail marketing campaigns), uploading images and tagging links.

Obs: It is important to mention that I had worked 6 months as CRM consultant in a digital marketing agency AD. DIALETO (Acquired by Accenture Group), where I had an opportunity to implement all the structure for e-CRM area, and at the same time developing the team hired by the agency giving technical training aimed at the best practices in the segment.

Digitalks Marketing & Services, Sao Paulo, Brazil | Jan 2011 – Mar 2012

- ➤ E-mail Marketing Analyst | Aug 2011 Dec 2012
- Marketing Assistant | Jan 2011 Jul 2011
- Organize and manage corporate events over 20 states in Brazil during a year.
- Contact speakers and define subjects according to their professional background.
- Rent hotels and service providers for the production and execution of the event.
- Support the sales team getting in touch with potential groups like Universities and Local Companies.
- Marketing strategy (Online and Offline) creating promotions for the target audience.
- Social media content management and report.

Nestle Brasil LTDA, Sao Paulo, Brazil | May 2008 – Oct 2010

- Public Affairs Analyst | Jan 2010 Oct 2010
- Public Affairs Intern | May 2008 Dec 2009
- Responsible for Identify potential contracts with the government and documentation research.
- Procurement process analysis, tax and invoice payments.
- Weekly sales analysis and preparation of management reports.
- Controlling and monitor the production and delivery of the products with the factories.
- Registration and License updated with a Governmental Agencies.

HSBC Bank Brasil S.A, Sao Paulo, Brazil | Mar2002 - Nov 2007

- Administrative Analyst | Jul 2003 Nov 2007
- > Administrative Intern | Mar 2002 Jun 2003
- Review of the administrative processes and document update.
- System tester and workflow review using new technologies and applications.
- Follow-up of internal customers and weekly reports of performance improvement.
- Updated receivables by totaling paid/unpaid invoices;
- Responsible for update spreadsheets and reports (weekly).

General Skills

- Language Skills: Portuguese (Native), English (Fluent), Spanish (Intermediate).
- **Email Marketing Summit 2016**: I could participate as a Speaker in the first Email Marketing Summit (2016) in São Paulo, an event organized by specialists in the area where the objective was to impact new professionals. My presentation addressed the importance of clusters and segmentation when you talk about e-Mail marketing.
- Computer Skills: JAVA, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Kotlin, Git/GitHub, JSON, Node JS, Microsoft Azure, Cisco Packet Tracer, NDG Linux, Android Studio, Adobe Package (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects), Oracle Cloud Server, Salesforce Cloud Server, Microsoft Office Package (Advanced); Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook.
- Extra Courses: E-Commerce Manager at Internet Innovation.

IT Essentials (Hardware and Software) at Cisco Network Academy. Networks (Network Routing and Switching) at Cisco Network Academy.

Volunteering

Working as a volunteer at Christ City Church Dublin since March/2018.

Interests

Music: Co-founder and Choir Singer at Caminho Cantante, an NGO created to teach choir practice and musical theory in Sao Paulo/Brazil from 2015 to 2016.

Sports: Swimming Referee at São Paulo Aquatic Federation, an Official Authority in the State of São Paulo/Brazil from 2014/ to 2016.

References

References upon request.